okay I have dessert for you a special
dessert now you're supposed to be a CI
teachers how many a CI courses are there
36 18 open courses and 18 yeah diamond
way courses but there's about eight
secret secret courses to eight or ten
anyway they're called practice module
okay say practice module and these are
how things you can use for your personal
practice so I didn't just write 36
courses I wrote a bunch of personal
practice courses okay and they're hidden
in all of the ACI courses if you're
gonna be a good a CI teacher I suggest
you explore those practice modules they
have special meditations special
practices you can do okay
now the one that I'm thinking about for
you guys this week is called tone man
you know tone man okay giving and taking
meditation if you're gonna be a good a
CI teacher you should have Tumlin in
your toolbox okay to be a good teacher
you should have a big toolbox okay many
many meditations that you know how to
teach okay
I think tonglen is the most important
meditation of all it's the first one you
should teach it's the last one you
should teach okay so this week I'd like
to give you some special teaching about
Tomlin ok and go deeper go deeper okay
[Music]
and it has how many parts oh my gosh how
many pins is that it's a hundred pages I
translate a 100 pages about tongue men
from many many many scriptures okay so
the whole thing is direct translation
about Tumlin and it goes very very deep
into the practice of tongue men okay so
we'll give you the reading okay Tim said
they can they're gonna have to print it
in Tucson I think maybe and you can talk
to him if you want to help but it's a
hundred pages we'll put it in your
notebook okay we'll give it to you to
put in your notebook and then I'll teach
you how to teach it okay so every night
we'll do a little bit tonglen you know
the basic meditation you learned it many
times but you can go deeper
there are probably a hundred books about
them and they go very deep
there's many deep prana practices
pranayama for tonglen okay yoga
practices for Tumlin so we're gonna go
through some of those okay and that's
just dessert okay alright and let's
start okay we have I'm gonna give you
ten minutes early so you like me and
then alright it's okay I also have to
write more homework huh yeah I know that
was in a different world
[Music]
okay
the first reading for Tomlin is from the
first pension mama okay who lived he
lived about a hundred years he's called
the Lama who lived a hundred years but
he was born we think he was born at
fifteen 66 or 67 he died in 1662 and
[Music]
that tongue land practice the classical
source is his one of his books okay
the famous source for Tung Yun is one of
the books of the first pension number
okay which is written about five hundred
years ago okay and there's a llama named
llama Quicksilver who's the famous llama
for King Kong you jumbo teaching Diamond
angel budget yogini okay and that's the
secret practice we do here if you do a
three-year retreat here you're gonna do
Ginga you German okay and so one of the
most important teachers explained where
you can find Tomlin okay and that's the
first reading then I'm gonna give you
okay it's a structure where does Tomlin
come in the structure of the lamrim okay
steps to Buddhahood where do we teach
tongue men okay where does tone then
come from okay here we go first you need
to study bodhichitta okay all right
what's the two parts of bodies inner hmm
makes your body suffer you wanna become
a Buddha so you can help everybody
that's all
that's different simcha upon
young buds Abidjan okay so in the lam
room we will study how to develop
compassion and that's based on Doc's an
EMG what's that yeah it's two steps also
everyone has an equal right to happiness
everyone in this room has equal rights
to get what they want
okay that's the first thing it's very
[Music]
kind of dharma democracy okay
everybody has equal right to be happy
everybody deserves to be happy okay you
don't have more right than the people
around you to be happy okay it's not
logical and it's not fair to work harder
for your happiness then you do for other
people that's prejudice that's what you
call it's racism or something you know
you are to work harder for yourself
happiness than for other people it's
unfair okay it's the worst kind of
unfair okay so you have to switch
yourself and other people okay so that's
that's where the tonglen starts in that
practice okay then we work on that and
then it goes into Tolman okay so where
does tonglen come from it comes from
that practice where you exchange
yourself and others okay you put
yourself in the other person's place
because they have equal right to be
happy okay and it's difficult because
whose hair do you call them every
morning whose teeth do you brush every
morning who do you feed every day so
carefully
it's always new so naturally we have
some prejudice prejudice right you take
care of yourself first and we have to
fight that project so Tomlin the purpose
of tullman meditation is to fight the
prejudice that says I deserve to be
happy more than you deserve to be happy
okay got it
that's the that's where Tong man comes
in the famous teaching where it was
first taught okay
all right then there's a lot then after
that comes the six perfections after
that comes the six perfections so Tomlin
comes before and then you can practice
Tantra all right then I put in some
readings there's two ways to develop but
it's in an email to famous methods to
develop love there are two famous
methods to develop love okay one is dr.
MJ okay you exchange yourself with
others okay equal right and the other is
the seven steps for developing love
where you realize that everyone has been
your mother okay based on the
understanding that everyone has been
your mother these are the two famous
ways to develop compassion okay
people go through big big expense and
they work so hard to take care of their
own mother okay and then they don't take
care of other people's mother so much
okay and in Buddhism everyone has been
your mother okay so you owe everybody
equally okay
you have equal responsibilities to
everybody okay so there's seven famous
steps for developing bodhichitta or you
can use duction dmg okay and the highest
coolest method is to mix them together
to thirteen steps okay you mix them
together with Tumlin with Tommen so now
you have the big three the big three
okay number one switch yourself with
other people
okay number two see that everyone has
been your mother and treat them that way
and then number three what do tonin do
Tony okay these are the and there's a
very secret practice where you combine
those three together okay you mix them
together it's very sweet it's in your
reading okay it's in your meeting and
it's thirteen steps okay it becomes
thirteen steps and we'll do it tomorrow
okay tomorrow all right
I think all of us we feel like oh I'm
not something wrong with me I don't love
people as much as the Buddha less people
you know there must be something wrong
with me all those body suffers they love
people a lot actually I don't like half
the people I mean am i a bad person in
my bad Buddhist you know no you just
didn't have these three trainings okay
then you can learn to love everybody
but you have to practice okay it's like
yoga okay you can't do what those Yogi's
do unless you do it every day
right you have to do it every day okay
so we'll talk about I don't know if
you're like me I feel guilty I'm teacher
I should love everybody
some people come to talk to me I
actually run away if I see them I go
around the corner then later I feel
guilty I'm not a good person I don't
love everybody equally you know so we'll
talk about it tomorrow
you mix Tumlin with shanty demos with
who did the seven steps instruction
audition
okay you mix these three methods how to
be a more loving person how to learn to
love it's not natural we don't have it
so I guess some people have it I don't
have it I need to practice how to be
loving okay
so we'll try it tomorrow we'll do a
meditation tomorrow okay all right
that's my introduction to because that's
the most important meditation you're
ever going to teach right and that 100
pages translation is so cool okay you
should study
you all did Tumlin it's the first
meditation they teach you in the
monastery and you keep doing it until
you die nobody stops the oldest monk in
the monastery is still doing tonglen
every day the baby monk seven years old
is turned on man okay you never stop
toning so if you're gonna be a
meditation teacher that's the first
meditation should teach and it's the
last meditation you should teach cool
and now you're gonna get the super
instructional burn